Luigi Antonini Curriculum Vitae

Profession

Application Architect, Developer

Personal Data

Date of birth: 03/02/1984Location: Terni , Italy

• Cap: 05100

• Military Position: Soldier exempt

• Patent: B

Education and Training

2008
 Graduated in Computer Engineering University "La Sapienza" of Rome

2002
 Diploma in Classical
 High School GC Tacito Terni

Contacts

• Email: <u>luigi.antonini84@gmail.com</u>

Website: www.luigiantonini.it

Blog: www.codeblog.it

• LinkedIn: http://it.linkedin.com/in/luigiantonini

Twitter: https://twitter.com/gigi_igigGitHub: https://github.com/gigiigig

Languages

• Italian : Mother tongue

 English: Good knowledge reading, Medium knowledge writing, Basic knowledge speaking

• French: Basic knowledge reading, writing and speaking

Summary

I'm software enthusiast, i love to search and test new technologies and development techniques.

I started developing web applications with JavaEE, tried desktop applications programming with C# and Java Swing, and web development with Php (Drupal, Wordpress) and nowadays, i'm working on Android platform.

However, since i met modern multi-paradigm languages (Scala, Ruby, Groovy), modern RAD frameworks (Gralis , Rails , Lift , Play) and modern BDD/TDD frameworks (Specs2, RSpec), these have become my main interest.

Skills

Operating Systems

Development on Linux (Ubuntu/Debian)
 Development on Windows (XP/Vista/7)
 Development on Mac Os
 Level: Good(5 years)
 Level: Good(1 year)

Server Administration

I'm able to configure Linux(Debian, Centos; Level: Basic(> 2 anni) server for web development with all the necessary services.
 (Apache, PHP, Java, Tomcat, MySQL, FTP, Ruby, RoR, rubygem, passenger, git, svn)

However, not having enough knowledge abou security, i'm not able to set up production machines.

Languages

o Programming Languages:

Java: Level: Good (5 years)

Frameworks:

Struts (1 year)

JPA, Hibernate (2 years)

Swing (1 year)

Spring (MVC, security), (<1 year)

Java on Android: Level: Medium (> 2 years)

Groovy Level: Medium (~ 1 year)

(Grails)

Scala Level: Basic (~ 6 months)

(Lift, Play!, Squeryl, Scala on Android)

Ruby On Rails Level: Basic (~ 6 months)

PHP: Level: Medium (> 2 years)

(Drupal, Wordpress)

JavaScript (CoffeeScript): Level: Good (4 years)

Frameworks: (jQuery,jQueryUI,JqueryMobile)

Web languages (Frontend)

HTML Level: Good (4 years)
CSS (LESS, SCSS) Level: Good (4 years)

o Database

SQL(MySql) Level: Good (4 years)

MongoDB Level: Basic

• Analysis and Design

UMLdiagram and ER diagram LogicLevel: BasicLevel: Basic

• Development Tools

 NetBeans
 Eclipse
 (EclipseJ2EE, Scala IDE, RadRails, AndroidToolkit, SpringToolSuite)
 Level: Good (3 years)
 Level: Good (3 years)

Drupal

Version 6
 Level: Medium(> 1 year)

Professional Experience

 April 2012 - Now
 Application Architect and Developer at GreenConsulting, Terni

Application Architect and Tech Lead Java/Scala Android Developer Java/Grails/Php Web Developer

I'm responsible for selection of technologies and give technical support for all company projects.

I'm responsible for design and development of Android applications, including web services and web administrations, and provide support for iOs development.

May 2010 - April 2012: Java, Grails, PHP Analyst and Programmer at GreenConsulting, Terni

Java Android Developer Java/Grails/Php Web Developer

I was responsible for both design and development of Android applications, including web services and web administration, developed with Grails and Php.

I worked on some web projects with Java (Spring , Hibernate , Quartz) and Php (Drupal , Wordpress).

I selected technologies used within the company for many projects.

April 2008 - October 2009: Java Analyst and Programmer at Trendiweb-Digitalmedia, Orte

The company is engaged in development of Web Applications , and mostly focused on development of WAP applications for mobile devices, like web games and multimedia contents delivery.

I worked as JavaEE developer with main technologies : Struts, Hibernate ,Quartz , JPA , JSF, EJB ,Tomcat

November 2007 - March 2008: Stage at Trendiweb SRL, Orte

I designed and developed a JavaEE web application that allows multimedia contents download for mobile devices.

Other experiences

September 2012 - November 2012 Online Course "Principles Functional Programming in Scala" supported by EPFL, Martin Odersky

Course of functional programming in Scala, promoted by the 'EPFL, held by Martin Odersky, the founder of Scala, through the platform Coursera. The course presents the programming language Scala applied to functional programming.

I finished the course with grade: 100%

March 2013 - May 2013

Online Course "Pattern-Oriented Software Architectures for Concurrent and Networked Software" supported by Vanderbilt University, Douglas C. Schmidt

This course teaches how to apply patterns, pattern languages, and frameworks to alleviate the complexity of developing concurrent and networked software.

I finished the course with grade: 100%

Other Projects

I worked on some projects for private clients and for my own experiments. Other main technologies with which i worked are:

Ruby On Rails C# .Net Framework Scala Play Framework 2 Lift Drupal , Wordpress MongoDB